Guide to the Rice University Jesse H. Jones Graduate School of Management records, 1974-2017 UA 148
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice University Jesse H. Jones Graduate School of Management records
1974-2017
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rice University
UA 148
14.5 Linear Feet (27 boxes)
This collection highlights the founding of the Jones School and its daily business from 1974-2013. Records contain information relating to the school's history, bylaws, directories, correspondence, press releases, awards. It also contains items regarding fundraising, projects, lectures and seminars, and various corporate and individual contributors to the school. The collection also features documents from various Rice University professors and administrators with ties to the Jones School.
Historical Note
The Jones Graduate School of Business is named after the late Jesse Holman Jones, a world-renowned business and civic leader. Born in Tennessee in 1874, Jones moved to Dallas in 1891, and then to Houston in 1898. He began his business career overseeing lumberyards and sawmills in East Texas and Louisiana, and soon after branched out into construction and banking as he oversaw the construction of some of Houston's tallest buildings in the early twentieth century. During World War I, Jones served as Director of Military Relief for the American Red Cross. Jones was called on for assistance by Presidents Hoover and Roosevelt, and served as chairman of the Rreconstruction Finance Corporation during the Great Depression, overseeing investments in various assistance programs. After serving as Secretary of Commerce during World War II, Jones focused more on his philanthropic efforts, funding various organizations devoted to the arts, environment and human services, as well as museums, scholarships, and student grants, mostly through his philanthropic organization, Houston Endowment, Inc. (excerpted from "Texas Highways," January 2009, p. 5).
The Jesse H. Jones Graduate School of Business received its initial funding in 1974 through a donation from the Houston Endowment. The Jones school offers multiple MBA degrees as well as an undergraduate minor, and its programs have been recognized throughout the world for fostering innovation and leadership. (excerpted from the Jones Graduate School of Business webpage, http://business.rice.edu/About_School.aspx, accessed June 6, 2011)
Scope and Contents
This collection highlights the founding of the Jones School of Management and its daily business from establishment of the school in 1974 through the ground breaking of the Jones School's new building in 2000. Records contain information relating to the school's founding and history, its bylaws, faculty and alumni directories, correspondences, press releases and newsclips, national accreditation, and awards. It also contains items regarding fundraising, various projects undertaken by the school, lectures and seminars, scholarships and grants, as well as documents related to the school's various corporate and individual contributors. The collection also features a significant holding of documents from many Jones School professors and instructors, as well as various Rice University professors and administrators with ties to the Jones School.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred to the Woodson Research Center, 2006-2008.
Index Terms
Subjects
Business; Business enterprises -- Texas -- Houston; Universities and colleges; Education
Document Types
notes; reports
- Series I: Founding and activities, 1974-2000, 119085
  - History, 95130 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Founding, 95131 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Funding, endowment, 95132 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Promotional, 95133 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Management programs, 95134 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Workshops, lectures, seminars, 95135 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Partners, 95136 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Bylaws, 95137 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Directories, 95138 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Newsclips, 95139 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Press releases, 95140 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Annual reports, 95141 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - "Executive News", 95142 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Scholarships, 95143 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Projects/proposals, 95144 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Luncheon series, 95145 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Recruiters guides, 95146 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - MBA application, 95147 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Invitations, awards, 95148 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Investiture of graduates, 95149 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Groundbreaking for new building, May 23, 2000, 95150 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - New building dedication, 95151 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Series II: Oversize materials, 95153
  - Woodson Courtyard, 95152 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Admissions information, 2000-2006 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Series III: Addendum covering 1976-1995, 95154
  - AACSB International Association for Management Education, 95155 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - AACSB Self-Evaluation VI, 95156 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - AACSB Issues in the 102nd Congress, 95157 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - AACSB Salary Surveys, 95158 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - AACSB Guide to Doctoral programs in Business and Management, 95159 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - AACSB Salary Surveys, 95160 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - AACSB Salary Surveys, part II, 95161 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - AACSB Issues, 95162 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
  - AACSB Rice University, Jones School, 95163 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Taylor, William M., 95164 (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
  - Tiller, Emerson, 95165 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Trask, Dick, 95166 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Verma, A., 95167 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Von Der Mehden, Fred, 95168 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Wedemeyer, Phil D., 95169 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Whitmeyer, Kathy, 95170 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Williams, Michael F., 95171 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Williams, Patti A., 95172 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Wilson, William R., 95173 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Yim, Bennett C., 95174 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Flex program, 95175 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Gifts / contributions, 95176 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Herring Hall – Activitiy report, 95177 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Herring Hall – Pledges and donations, 95178 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Acknowledgements, 1989, 95179 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Acknowledgements, 1988, 95180 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Acknowledgements, 1987, 95181 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Proposals T-XYZ, 95182 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Prospective donors / fundraising, 95183 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Fundraising article from New York Times magazine, 4/2/1989, 95184 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Sponsors, inactive, 95185 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - American General Corporation, 95186 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Arthur Young Foundation, 95187 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Cooper Industries Foundation, 95188 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Cullen Bank, 95189 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - First Republic Bank – Fannin, 95190 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Houston Wire and Cable, 95191 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - MBank Houston (Member of MCorp), 95192 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Soltex Polymer Corporation (Solvay America), 95193 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Sounthdown, Inc., 95194 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Touche Ross & Co., 95195 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Underwood Neuhaus and Co., 95196 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Union Bank of Houston, 95197 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Walter Pye's, 95198 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - United Gas Pipeline Company, 95199 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Capital bank, N.A., 95200 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - The Coastal Corp., 95201 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Charter Bancshares, Inc., 95202 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - The Continental Group, Inc., 95203 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Distribution Systems, Inc., 95204 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Geosource, Inc., 95205 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Gulf Resources and Chemical Group, 95206 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Highland Resources, 95207 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Gerald D. Hines Interests, 95208 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Houston Lighting and Power Co., 95209 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Abraham, Abraham, 95210 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Barr, Robert, 95211 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Bishop, Marguerite "Peggy", 95212 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Blair, Ed, 95213 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Boatwright, John B., 95214 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Bridges, Eileen, 95215 (Box 10, Folder 9-10)
  - Carroll, James W., 95216 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Ciliske, Kathleen, 95217 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Coombes, Robert, 95218 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Cozby, James, 95219 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Cramer, Dwight, 95220 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Dichev, Ilia, 95221 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Driskill, L., 95222 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Duke, Cullen A., 95223 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Dunn, Craig, 95224 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Friday, A. Randall, 95225 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Ferrill, June, 95226 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Gemeinhardt, G., 95227 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Gessler, Mark, 95228 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Greanias, George, 95229 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Griffin, Campbell, 95230 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Gottleib, David, 95231 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Gow, Robert H., 95232 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Guttman, Amir, 95233 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Harlan, William A., 95234 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Hauser, Nickolaus, 95235 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Hermance, R., 95236 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Hewitt, Charles H., 95237 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Johnston, Holly Hanson, 95238 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Johnson, William A., 95239 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Kehoe, John K., 95240 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Khumawala, Basheer, 95241 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Kirby, C., 95242 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Klein, Jeannine, M.E., 95243 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Lewis, Marvin, 95244 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Lewis, Patricia N., 95245 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Long, Linda, 95246 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Mackey, William S., 95247 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - McCormack, John, 95248 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Meakin, Christopher, 95249 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Miller, Christopher, 95250 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Murray, Fred F., 95251 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Rankine, Graeme W., 95252 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Rankine, Graeme W. Folder 2, 95253 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Rau, R., 95254 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Reid, Donald J., 95255 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Rosthal, Susan S., 95256 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Sabalos, James C., 95257 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Seidl, John (Mick), 95258 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Shaddix, Mallory, 95259 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Shockley, Richard L., 95260 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Silversteen, Gordon, 95261 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Stice, Earl K., 95262 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Stobaugh, Robert B., 95263 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Sutton, Neal, 95264 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Coopers and Lybrand, 95265 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Lifemark Corporation, 95266 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Criterion Group, 95267 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Phillips International Company, 95268 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Talent Tree Companies, 95269 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Mr. and Mrs. Nathan M. Avery, 95270 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - E.D. Butcher, 95271 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Houston Oil and Minerals Corporation, 95272 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Hughes Tool Company, 95273 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Service Corporation International, 95274 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Brown Challenge and Rice Associates, 95275 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Steuben Owls, 95276 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - DeCrane Dinner 2.3.93, 95277 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Siart Dinner 2.2.94, 95278 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Goizueta Dinner 4.6.94, 95279 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Houston Natural Gas Corporation, 95280 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Benefactors Wall Plaque, 95281 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Dedication of Herring Hall November 9, 1984, 95282 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - '76 JGS Mission Statement, 95283 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Focus on Rice- The Jones Graduate School- Spring '88, 95284 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Jones School- Faculty and Staff Directory, 95285 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Jones School Inaugural Dinner, 95286 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Jesse H. Jones Graduate School of Administration, 95287 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Jesse H. Jones (Pantheon of Philanthropy), 95288 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Materials, 95289 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Sponsor Program, 95290 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Jesse H. Jones School Educational Investment Fund Proposal, 95291 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - JGSSA, 95292 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Draft Report of the Steering Committee 11/96, 95293 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - OED- Office of Executive Development, 95294 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - 1993 JGS Graduating Students Placement Meeting September 9, 1992, 95295 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - JGS of Administration, 95296 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Self Study, 95297 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Recognition for Excellence, 95298 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - 1991 Chron Files, 95299 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - 1991 Chron Files Part II, 95300 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - 1990 Chron Files, 95301 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - 1990 Chron Files Part II, 95302 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Deans Seminar, 95303 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Deans Seminars '92-'93, 95304 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Deans Seminar (historical file), 95305 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Deans Seminar Speakers- No Response 1989-1990, 95306 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Women Speaker Invitations to Deans Seminar- 1990, 95307 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - 1990-91 Ideas for Deans Seminars, 95308 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Deans Seminar Speakers (info), 95309 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Bailar-Chron '95-'97, 95310 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Bailar-Chron '95-'97, 95311 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Bailar Chron, 1994, 95312 (Box 19, Folder 1-2)
  - Correspondence Chron, 95313 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Bailar Chron, 1992, 95314 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Bailar to faculty, 1987-1995, 95315 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Bailar correspondence, general, 95316 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Bailar, annual reports, 95317 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - JGS directories, 1993-1994, 95318 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Friends of JGS, 95319 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Faculty, 95320 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Bailar – Rupp items for discussion, 95321 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Bailar – Gillis items for discussion, 95322 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - 1990 Economic Summit, Houston, 95323 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Bailar, staff meetings, 1992, 95324 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Dean's Seminar, 1995, 95325 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Dean's Seminar, 1994-1995, 95326 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Jim Kinsey discussions, 95327 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Harry Wilkinson, 95328 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Student Investment Fund Project, 95329 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Feron Wiley, 95330 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Bailar chron file, 1991, 95331 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Building, JGS, 95332 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Publicity, Herring Hall, 95333 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Tuggle, general correspondence, 95334 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Ratings, 95335 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Budgets, 95336 (Box 22, Folder 3-4)
  - Child care services, 95337 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Probations and dismissals, 95338 (Box 23, Folder 1-2)
  - Bailar chron file, 1992, 95339 (Box 23, Folder 3)
- Series IV: Addendum covering 2005-2008-2017, 119065
  - Follies, DVD-format, 2005-2008, 2013, 119067 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Investiture, DVD-format, 2005-2008, 119068 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Admission standards, 1991 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Faculty position request, 1992 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Financial status, 1991 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Gifts, 1991 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Managerial Studies Program, 1992 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Memos, 1991-1992 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Curriculum and Standards Committee faculty retreat, 1993 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Strategic planning, 1984, 1996 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Strategic plan, 2006 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Architectural Program statement, 1998-1999 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Alumni meeting, ca. 1995 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Rice Leaders workshop, 2008-05-11-2008-05-13 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Newsclips (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Investiture of graduates, 1981-1999 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Investiture of graduates, 2004-2010 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Investiture of graduates, 2011-2017 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Business Information Center, 1970s-1980s (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Accreditation maintenance, 2007 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Recognition of excellence, 1989, 1995 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - External review, 1996-1998 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Long range planning, 1978-1979 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Founding proposal/history (Box 26, Folder 9)
- Series V: Addenda - oversized
  - Certificate naming Gilbert R. Whitaker as the holder of the H. Joe Nelson, III Chair in the Jones Graduate School of Administration, 1988 (Box 27)
  - Birthday sign to Dean Whitaker from students, 1997-10-08 (Box 27)
  - Certificate honoring Gilbert R. Whitaker from the Rice Board of Trustees, 2005-05-26 (Box 27)
  - Certificate naming the Gilbert and Ruth Whitaker Business Information Center, 2005-06-24 (Box 27)